霍华德的太空舱
Howard's capsule should be reentering
马上就要到大气层了
the atmosphere any minute.
他回来我挺开心的
It'll be good to have him back.
神奇四侠重聚首
The Fantastic Four reunited!
这段时间表现不错  假沃罗威茨
Yeah, you had a good run, fake Wolowitz.
我们会怀念你的好
We'll remember you with nostalgic fondness.
就像我们怀念早年的拨号路由器  录像带
The way we do the dial-up modem, the VHS tape, or...
以及莱纳德的健身房会员资格
or Leonard's gym membership.
干嘛人家回来就踢他走
We're not kicking him out.
我跟他也成了好哥们
Stuart and I have become good friends.
一票赞成  一票反对
Okay, one vote for, one vote against.
莱纳德你决定吧
Leonard, you're the tiebreaker.
我对他留下没意见啊
I don't have a problem with stuart.
他店里的东西还给我们打八折呢
Besides, he gives us a 20% discount at his comic book store.
我的友谊没这么廉价
Well, I don't sell my friendship that cheaply.
我可以打七折
I can go 30.
欢迎加入  好兄弟
Welcome aboard, old chum.
好的  太空署的网站显示
Okay, the NASA website says
太空舱降落的最后一段开始了
Howard's final descent has begun.
去时还是男孩
He left a boy,
回时已成男孩身材的英雄
he returns a boy-sized hero.
麦圈客  冷静
Loops, calm down!
我们的天主[希伯来语]
Baruch ata Adonoy,
宇宙的君王
Eloheinu melech ha-olam,
是您将面包带来人间
ha-motzi lechem min ha-aretz.
唱的啥啊
What's that?
犹太人吃面包时的祷文
The Jewish prayer for eating bread!
犹太人没有从太空回归的祈祷文
We don't have one for falling out of space!
成功了
We did it!
我们安全着陆  活下来了
We're on the ground! We survived!
刚才只是开降落伞
That was just the parachute.
离着陆还有六英里呢
We still have another six miles to go.
生活大爆炸 第六季第四集
载荷专家沃罗威茨
曼德尔
我是接我老公的机
Waiting for my husband.
挺好的
That's nice.
他刚从太空回来
He's coming back from outer space.
这飞机是从休斯顿过来的吧
I think this flight's coming from Houston.
我是说  他...
No, I mean, he...
算啦  没事
Never mind.
-他来啦  -华仔  华仔
- There he is! - Howie! Howie!
谢谢各位
Whoa, thank you.
回到地球感觉真好
Great to be back on Earth.
他们是来找我的  林戈
Uh, I think they're here for me, Ringo.
林戈·斯塔尔  曾任披头士鼓手  有着与犹太人相似的外表
曼德尔先生  我是您的司机
Mr. Mandel, I'm your driver.
霍华德·曼德尔  美国著名主持人  也有霍依[华仔]的称呼
好的  谢谢
Oh, thanks.
那疯子在飞机上跟大家说
That nut job was telling everybody on the plane
他是宇航员
he's an astronaut.
我好想你
I missed you so much!
我也想你
I missed you, too.
其他人呢
Where are the guys?
只有我来
Oh, it's just me.
我懂了
Oh, I get it.
他们在家等着给我办惊喜派对
They're waiting back home with a big surprise party.
别担心  我可以假装惊喜
Don't worry, I can act surprised.
没有  我让他们明晚再见你
No, I told them they could have you tomorrow night.
今晚你是我的
Tonight, you belong to me.
保重  你没事吧
Gesundheit. You okay?
你回来了  我当然没事
I am now that you're back.
走吧  咱们回家
Come on, let's go home
老娘要扒了你的裤子
so I can tear off those little pants.
好的  但提醒你件事
Great. Just keep in mind
宇航员的肌肉张力会减弱
astronauts lose a lot of muscle tone in space,
所以今晚的"重活"大多得靠你了
so you might have to do most of the heavy lifting.
我好失望哦
You know, I am very disappointed
今晚不能给霍华德
that I won't be able to celebrate
庆祝他的成就
Howard's accomplishment tonight.
我也是  但明天就能见他啦
Me, too. But we'll see him tomorrow.
只是这是我认识他的这些年来
Yes, it's just that in all the years I've known him,
他从未有过机会得到我的赞赏
he's never had the opportunity to receive my admiration.
本来还期待看他得到赞赏时
I was excited to see the look on his face
脸上那表情呢
when it finally happened.
你真是奇葩
You're unbelievable.
人中龙凤是谓奇葩
I know.
你画我猜
All right, Pictionary--
怎么分队
what are the teams?
男女分队如何
How about boys versus girls?
这会不会不太公平
Oh! That hardly seems fair.
我加入任何一队
But I guess any team that I'm not on
都是对其他队伍的不公平
has a decided disadvantage.
再次觉得你奇葩
Once again, unbelievable.
再次回你  鹤立鸡群是谓奇葩
Yeah, once again, I know.
来吧  第一回合
All right, round one.
这是题目
Here.
-好的  -来吧
- Got it. - Okay.
准备  开始
Ready, set, go.
盒子吗
Uh, box?
窗子吗
Uh, window?
蝙蝠侠
Batman.
蝙蝠侠与罗宾
Batman and Robin.
神奇双胞胎与他们的猴子
Uh, Wonder Twins plus the monkey.
神奇双胞胎与猴子加蝙蝠侠
Wonder twins plus the monkey and Batman.
礼  礼物
A gift? Present!
礼物  没错
Present! Yeah!
莱纳德
Oh... Leonard.
这么明显了你还猜不出啊
Now, how can you not get that?
你画的是哪门子的礼物啊
In what universe is that a present?
不是礼物
It's not a present,
是现在[一字多义]
it's the present. Look.
你看  这是你我
There's you and me.
这是佩妮和艾米
It's Penny and Amy.
我们正在玩"你画我猜"
We're playing Pictionary.
就是"现在"
In the present.
天啊  我们会虐死他们
Oh, my God, we're gonna kill them.
是夸克胶子等离子体
It's a quark-gluon plasma.
不对
No.
夸克胶子等离子体中的
It's asymptotically free partons
渐进自由量子
inside a quark-gluon plasma.
和夸克无关
Nothing with quarks.
是对冷暗物质模型的
It's an observational rebuttal
观测反例
of the Lambda-Cdm Model of the universe!
不对
No!
-是巧克力豆饼干  -正确
- It's a chocolate chip cookie! - Yes!
你怎么可能猜不到这个
How could you miss that?
你要人猜出"巧克力豆饼干"
Hey, if you want someone to guess "chocolate chip cookie,"
就得在旁边画上一杯牛奶啊
you draw a glass of milk next to it.
-佩妮就猜到了  -那是因为
- Penny got it. - Yeah, only after
我帮她把其他可能的答案都排除了
I eliminated all the obvious answers.
不用谢我
You're welcome.
香肠
Oh, uh, uh, uh, sausage.
德国腊肠
Uh, uh, uh, uh, bratwurst?
热狗肠
Oh, oh, a hot dog.
佩妮  你还不开始画吗
Penny, aren't you gonna draw something?
放心  时间充足  这一幕不可错过啊
Relax, we got time, this is so fun.
看这个
There.
太阳系
A solar system.
那个  那个
Uh, uh, uh,
不明飞行德国猪肝肠  啥啊
Uh, um, unidentified flying liverwurst? I don't...
该画了吧
Now?
再等会
Soon.
拜托  莱纳德
Come on, Leonard,
我答案都递到你嘴边了啊
I am spoon-feeding this to you.
我不知道
I don't know, uh...
喝醉了的鬼马小精灵
Casper the alcoholic ghost?
行了  戏看够了
All right, that's enough.
手
Uh, hand.
-指甲...指甲油  -答对了
- Uh, nail... polish? - Yep!
不对  等一下
Wait, no, no!
那个词是"波兰的"
The word is "Polish."
"波兰的"与"指甲油"只有大小写之分
看  波兰的大香肠
See, look. Polish sausage.
由尼古拉·哥白尼提出的太阳系学说
And the-the model of the solar system developed
他是波兰裔的天文学家
by Nicolaus Copernicus, a Polish astronomer.
最后
And then, finally,
如果还不够充分  虽然那是不可能的
if that wasn't enough-- which it should've been--
这是被她所发现的镭的辐射
This is Madame Curie killing herself
害死的居里夫人
by discovering Radium, who,
尽管她后来加入了法国籍
although she was a naturalized French citizen,
可她出生时是波兰的人
was Polish by birth!
不好意思  那个词明明是指甲油
Excuse me, the word is "polish."
看到没  是小写的p
See? Small "p."
还真的是小写
So it is.
这道题我俩各打五十大板吧
I guess we both share blame on this one.
妮妮   你还好吧
Bernie, you okay?
我马上就出来
Yeah, I'll be right there.
我不在的时候  你新养了一头海狮吗
Did you get a sea lion while I was gone?
我有点过敏而已
It's just allergies.
那就好
Okay.
吃点抗过敏药  就没事了
Took some benadryl. I'll be fine.
好了
So...
你想我吗
Did you miss me?
你觉得呢   每一分钟我都
Are you kidding? Every minute of every...
抱歉哦
Excuse me.
亲爱的  我们不用急着干这事
Sweetie, we don't have to do this now.
当然要啦
Yes, we do.
我们刚结婚你就出发了
You left right after we got married.
这算是我俩的蜜月呢
This is like our honeymoon.
现在
Now,
你给我坐稳了
hold on to your hat.
你没事吧
You okay?
有点头晕
A little dizzy.
一定是过敏药的关系
Must be the benadryl.
咱们换个体位吧
Switch places with me.
好的
Okay.
现在
Now...
快亲我
...Kiss me!
伯纳黛特
Bernadette?
妮妮  妮妮
Bernie? Bernie?
刚才真是爽爆了
That was amazing.
你让我高潮迭...
You made me feel things I never...
又快完事又有点小恶心啊
Well, that was quick and a little gross.
现在我了解她过去的感受了
Now, I know how she feels.
谢尔顿  你不是知道
Hey, Sheldon, you're always
很多小趣闻吗
full of fun little facts.
"虐得你屁滚尿流"这句话
Where did the expression
语源是从哪来的啊
"got your ass handed to you" come from?
我不知道
Don't know.
我猜这一定是古罗马的谚语
I wonder if it's from, like, ancient Rome
他们会把输家的屁股切下来
where they'd actually chop somebody's ass off
让输家看着屁股在地上滚
and then go, "here."
你懂得  也算是给"失败者之神"的献礼
You know, to appease Loseroneous, the god of losers.
我不是失败者
I am not a loser.
"你画我猜"根本就比不出人的智商和能力
Pictionary is not a true test of any real intelligence or skill.
公平地说
Mmm, in all fairness,
"你画我猜"包含了词汇量和绘图能力
Pictionary has verbal skills, visual skills.
算是很全面的游戏了
It's a pretty well-rounded game.
巧克力豆饼干都画不好的人
Lot of big talk from a man
还敢在此大放厥词
who can't draw a chocolate chip cookie.
算了  你再选一个游戏吧
All right, fine, pick another game.
艾米和我照样虐得你一败涂地
Amy and I will beat you at anything.
好啊
All right.
那我们玩
Let's play...
"西班牙物理嘉年华"
Physics Fiesta.
拜托  那是什么
Oh, come on, what is that?
我刚发明的游戏
It's a game that I just invented,
玩家得用西班牙语回答物理问题
in which the participants answer physics questions in remedial Spanish.
希格斯玻色子在哪里[西语]
Donde esta el boson de higgs?
在粒子加速器里[西语]
En el acelerador de particulares.
干得好  我的朋友[西语]
Bueno, mi amigo.
不  我们才不玩现编出来的蠢游戏
No, no, we're not playing some dumb made-up game.
哪个游戏不是编出来的
All games are made up.
那又不是大自然的产物
They're not found in nature.
当年又不是在地上挖洞时  碰巧找到的
You don't just dig in the ground, come across
拳击机械人大战系列玩具
a rich vein of rock'em sock'em robots.
换个游戏吧
Just pick another game.
我们可以玩点体育类游戏
Why don't we do something athletic
比如去大学的泳池玩水球
like go over to the university pool and play water polo?
不行  谢尔顿下水就沉
No good-- Sheldon doesn't float.
确实如此
That is true.
我的体密度比平常人高
I have a higher than normal body density.
泡澡的水放太多  我都可能会淹死
If I run too deep a bath, I drown.
那就玩点简单的吧
All right, let's keep it simple.
飞镖怎么样
How about darts?
不行  这个也不公平
Oh, that's not fair either.
怎么不行
Why not?
飞镖是酒吧里的游戏
Darts is a bar game.
你一到法律年龄就天天在那儿混了
You've been frequenting drinking establishments since you were of legal age.
是啊  她到那年纪"才开始"
Yeah, that's when it started.
总之  对于一切酒吧游戏
Well, regardless, she has a distinct advantage
她都有很大优势
in all tavern- based competitions.
台球  啤酒乒乓  湿衣比赛
Pool, beer pong, wet T-shirt contests--
湿衣比赛: 女士不穿内衣只穿T恤往身上倒水
由男士来评判哪位身材最佳
这些都不行
they're all out.
好吧
Okay.
不过我得声明一下
Just for the record,
我从来没参加过湿衣比赛
I have never entered a wet T-shirt contest.
我赢过  但是因为我醉时喝酒洒了一身
I've won a few, but that's just because I spill when I'm drunk,
所以
So...
我们可以去加州大学的尸体实验室
We could go to the cadaver lab at UCLA
玩真人版手术游戏
and play real-life operation.
-不  -不要
- No. - I don't think so.
确定吗  虽然鼻子不会发亮
Are you sure? I mean, the nose doesn't light up,
手术游戏:  对玩具人偶做手术
犯错时病人鼻子会发红光  并全身震动
但如果尸体足够新鲜
but if the corpse is fresh enough,
偶尔还是能让他腿抽抽呢
sometimes you can get the leg to jerk.
妈  小星星亮晶晶
Hey, Ma, twinkle, twinkle,
你的小星儿回家啦
your little star is home!
妈  解一下门链子
Ma, the chain's on the door!
霍华德
Howard?
我还以为要明天才能见到你呢
I thought I wasn't going to see you till tomorrow!
小妮妮身体不太舒服
Yeah, well, Bernie's not feeling well,
所以我就来看看你嘛
so I thought I'd stop by,
给你讲讲我人生中最棒的历险故事
tell you about the greatest adventure of my life,
听听你会怎么打击我
see if you can make me feel bad about it.
好的  稍等  我有点衣冠不整
Uh, uh, okay, hold on, I'm not decent!
好的
All right.
20年来都没解开过睡衣
Woman hasn't tied her robe in 20 years.
我一不在她就衣冠不整啦
Suddenly she's not decent?
你想我躲在衣柜还是从后门开溜
You want me to hide in the closet or go out the back?!
嘘  你得小点声
Shh, you need to whisper.
妈  谁在里面呢
Ma, who is in there?
没人  是电视的声音
Uh, nobody! The TV is on!
我只找到一只袜子
I only got one sock.
另一只跑哪去了
Where's my other sock?
那是谁啊
Who is that?
说了是电视里的对话
I told you, it's the TV.
杰·雷诺[主持人]丢了一只袜子  太逗了
Jay Leno lost a sock; it's hilarious.
你要是忙的话  我可以回头再来
If you're busy, I can come back.
稍微等我一下
Just give me a second!
快走快走
Go, go, go, go.
施耐德医生
Dr. Schneider?
你好  霍华德
Oh, hello, Howard.
你在这儿做什么呢
What are you doing here?
上门看病来了
Um, house call.
可你是个牙医啊
You're a dentist.
没错  我是牙医
Yes, yes, I am.
他好像发现我们有猫腻了
I think he's on to us!
好了  摘下眼镜
Okay, glasses off.
找到沃尔多
Find Waldo.
《寻找沃尔多》  在书中密密麻麻的人群中
找出主角沃尔多
快点  找到他  找到他
Hurry up, find him, find him.
我在看呢  别对我大吼大叫的
I'm trying! Don't yell at me!
我的老天  他戴了帽子  眼镜
For goodness' sake, he's wearing a hat, glasses,
穿着红条上衣
and a red striped shirt.
我知道他长什么样
I know what he looks like.
在这儿呢  我找着他了
Oh, there he is, I got him.
真棒  我们又赢了
Yes, we win again!
你怎么会找不到他
How could you not find him?
因为他不好找
Because he's hard to find.
如果好找的话
If he was easy to find,
这游戏就该改名《沃尔多在这里》了
The books would be called There's Waldo.
57  58  59
57, 58, 59,
一分钟到了
that's one minute.
长除法  长除法
Long division, long division.
快去快去
Go, go, go.
得写出计算过程哦
Remember, show your work.
我没事
I'm okay.
一点也不好
I'm not okay.
快起来  总不能连数学都输吧
Get up, we can't lose in math.
-37  -干得好
- 37! - Yes!
各就各位  预备  摔跤
Ready, set, wrestle.
1  2  3  倒下
One, two, three, pin.
别这样
Stop that.
艾米  帮个忙啊
Amy, do something.
艾米  救命
Amy, help.
艾米  别这样
Amy, stop that.
艾米  佩妮  你们两个快停下
Amy, Penny, both of you, stop it.
传送一人上舰[星际迷航]
One to beam aboard?
我的天  你回来了
Oh, my God, you're back.
瞧你
Oh, look at you.
你看起来好像长高了
You, you look like you grew.
是啊
Yeah.
失重状态拉松了我的脊柱
The lack of gravity did decompress my spine,
所以我高了3.8厘米
so I'm like an inch and a half taller.
趁我没缩水前  我明天就去车管局
I'm going to the DMV tomorrow to get my license changed
改驾照资料
before I shrink back.
请进  请进
Oh, uh, come in, come in.
我原以为要等到明天
Oh, I, uh, I didn't think I was going to get
才能见到你
to see you until tomorrow.
天气转凉  伯纳黛特身体不适
Yeah, well, Bernadette's a little under the weather
我妈则被我的牙医压在了身下
and my mom's kind of under my dentist.
你妈和你的牙医上床吗
Wait, your, your mother is sleeping with your dentist?
前牙医
Former dentist.
我要换一个  我知道他的手摸过"什么"了
I need a new one now that I know where his hands have been.
所以你是在一个人到处晃悠吗
So you're wandering all around by yourself?
从太空凯旋而归的英雄
That's not the kind of hero's welcome
可不应该受到这种待遇啊
an astronaut should come home to.
没事的  咱们太空牛仔
It's okay, you know, we space cowboys
舍身为科学图的不是名与利
don't do what we do for glory and fame.
这些甜头就留给摇滚明星  运动明星
We leave that to your rock stars and your athletes
和霍伊·曼德尔好了
and your Howie Mandels.
哥们儿  欢迎回来
Oh, hey, man, welcome back.
斯图尔特  多谢了
Oh, Stuart, thanks.
你在这儿干嘛
What are you doing here?
我现在算是住在这里了
I, I kind of live here now.
字面意  在他的脚上
直到他的生活回归正轨
Just until he gets back on his feet,
看起来非常帅气哦
which are looking pretty good
这双靴子是我送给他的生日礼物
in the boots I bought him for his birthday.
他好宠我  我爱死了
Ah, he's spoiling me and I love it.
你们现在是好兄弟了吗
Wow, so you guys are like buds now?
是啊  我们总是玩在一起
Oh, yeah, we hang out all the time.
而且  他没有女朋友
Plus, he doesn't have a girlfriend,
我也没有女朋友
I don't have a girlfriend.
就好像我和他的生活都有空洞之处
It's like we both had these holes in our lives,
而现在我们彼此填补了这个"空洞"
but now we fill each other's holes.
这话咱们老美听起来会觉得怪怪的
That sounds a little funny to an American ear.
-哪部分  -从头到尾
- Which part? - Just all of it.
好啦  你们今晚有什么安排
Okay, so w-what do you guys got going on tonight?
拉杰要带我去"音乐之声二人唱"
Raj is taking me to the sound of music sing-along.
"音乐之声二人唱"
Sound of music sing-along?
以前是咱俩的活动  不过没关系
That used to be our thing, but that's cool.
霍华德  这依然是我们的活动
Oh, Howard, it's still our thing.
和我们一起去  我们给你弄张黄牛票
Come with us, we'll, we'll get you a scalped ticket.
去了然后一个人坐旁边吗
So I'd be sitting by myself?
我们可以换着坐
We'll switch.
中场休息后你可以和我一起坐
You'll come sit with me after intermission.
那唱《雪绒花》时我岂不是孤零零的一个人
So I-I-I'd be sitting by myself during "Edelweiss"?
不  你们去吧  玩得开心点
No, no, you guys go. Have fun.
好吧  我们明天见吗
Okay, uh, will I get to see you tomorrow?
当然了  回见了  斯图尔特
Absolutely. See you, Stuart.
回见
Yeah, yeah.
他是不是长高了
Is he taller?
至少我妈还让她男朋友逃窗走
At least my mother made her boyfriend climb out the window.
好了  标准集市吃馅饼大赛的规则是
All right, standard state fair pie-eating contest rules are:
不许用手  最先吃完的人获胜
No hands, first one to clean the pan wins.
数到三就开始
On the count of three.
-一  二  -等等
- One, two... - Wait.
我有点担心
I'm a little concerned.
蓝莓富含抗氧化物
Blueberries are rich in antioxidants.
怎样
So?
吃了这么多抗氧化物
So, with all those antioxidants,
那我的氧化物没了怎么办
what if I run out of oxidants?
谢尔顿  咱俩一整晚输得一塌糊涂
Sheldon, we haven't won a game all night.
所以要么你把脸埋在馅饼里
Now, you either stick your face in that pie
要么我把那馅饼往你脸上埋
or I'm gonna stick that pie in your face.
太粗鲁了
That's rude.
一  二  三  开吃
One, two, three, eat.
伙计们  猜猜谁从太空回来了
Hey, guys, guess who's back from space.
不是时候
Not now!
蓝莓卡鼻孔了
Oh, ow, blueberry in my nose,
blueberry in my nose!
吸进去继续吃
Snort it down and keep eating!
你看起来有点面熟
You look familiar.
不太可能
I don't think so.
没错  我刚在新闻上看到你了
Yeah, I just saw you on the news.
你是个宇航员
You're an astronaut.
是的
Yes.
我是
Yes, I am.
好样儿的
Good for you.
来块免费芝士蛋糕怎么样
How about a piece of cheesecake on the house?
太谢谢你了
Oh, thank you so much.
我今天晚上倒霉到家了
I've been having the worst night.
我刚回来  我朋友们不在乎
I just got back, and my friends don't care,
我老婆病了  我去我妈家
my wife's sick, I went to my mom...
再废话看你吃不吃得着
You want the cheesecake or not?
来吧  多谢了
Yes, please.
英国摇滚歌手埃尔顿·约翰的歌曲  《火箭男》
* 我想这会是一段很长的时间 *
* And I think it's gonna be a long, long time *
* 直到降落  我才发现 *
* till touchdown brings me 'round again to find *
* 我不再是人们在家中看到我的那个人 *
* I'm not the man they think I am at home *
* 我是个火箭男 *
* I'm a rocket man. *
"喜上加喜"啊
Perfect.